ortfolio: wzrdistaken.github.io | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/benrwastake

t::hashed\_string const propertyComponentRef, entt::hashed\_str pertyOata const\* const propertyOataOverride) NABI\_NOEXCEPT Loop through all of the component's properties defined in xml (ComponentData& componentData: componentData)

vverrideEntityComponents(std::vector<ComponentData>& componentData
tty backed string const propertyComponentRef, entt::hashed\_string

// If the property is referencing this componen
if (componentData.m\_Id == propertyComponentRef)

# **PROFILE**

I am a Gameplay Engineer with over a years' industry experience working on Forza Horizon 5 and an as yet unannounced title. I am experienced with C++, C#, Unity & Unreal, and hold a first-class degree in Games Technology. I have also built a number of personal projects, including a C++ game engine and released a game on Steam. For details on these projects and more, please see my portfolio.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Playground Games** — Gameplay Engineer

September 2024 - Present, Leamington Spa

• Feature development for an unannounced project, primarily using C++.

June 2022 - June 2023, Leamington Spa (placement year)

- C++ & C# development in bespoke engine for Forza Horizon 5 on the Gameplay and Live teams.
- Shipped Horizon Rally Adventure DLC and Event Lab 2.0 on Xbox and PC.
- Investigated, planned and produced end to end automated testing solution using BotBrain.
- Collaborated internationally with Microsoft Studios based in the USA and Poland.

## **SKILLS**

#### Technical

C++, C#, Version Control (Perforce/Git), Testing, Continuous Integration (TeamCity), Visual Studio

### **Engines**

Bespoke C++ Engine @ Playground, DirectX (own engine), Unity, Unreal / Visual Scripting

#### Personal

Teamwork, Communication, Presentation, Planning, Time Management, Mentoring, Leadership

### Miscellaneous

Steam API, Xbox & PS SDK, Python, VR, Rust, Power BI, Kusto, Web (HTML/JS), Teams/Office Suite, Korean

## **EDUCATION**

# University of the West of England — Games Technology BSc (Hons)

### UWE is TIGA Accredited

September 2020 - June 2024, Bristol

- Grade: 1st Class. Nominated for TIGA Programmer Of The Year & received 3 Dean's List awards.
- Notable Projects: Nabi Allocator (C++ memory allocator) & Project ZipZap (released on Steam).
- Senior Engineer at <u>The Foundry</u> in-house studio in my final year.
- Gained ILM Award in Effective Mentoring whilst supporting first year students.

## Lord Williams School - A Level & GCSE

September 2013 - June 2020, Thame

• 3 A Levels, grade A & 9 GCSEs, grades 7-8, including Maths (7) and English (8).